A Finding Aid to the David Bourdon papers, 1941-1998, in the Archives of American Art AAA.bourdavi
Archives of American Art
- Research files, 1945-1998; 3; 25.8 Linear feet Boxes 2-28, 39
  - Andy Warhol, 1960-1998; 3.8; 2.8 Linear feet Boxes 24-26, 39
    - Obituary, 1987 (Box 26, Folder 8)
    - Obituary, Funeral Mass etc, 1980-1989 (Box 26, Folder 9)
    - Photographs - Miscellaneous, circa 1987-1989 (Box 26, Folder 10)
    - Pictures [with Notes], 1965-1989 (Box 26, Folder 11)
    - Pictures Material - 1960s, 1966-1988 (Box 26, Folder 12)
    - Pictures - 1980s, circa 1980-1989 (Box 26, Folder 13)
    - Pictures 4.1.1989 (Box 26, Folder 14)
    - Portraits, 1975-1987 (Box 26, Folder 15)
    - Portraits - 1970s and 1980s, 1970-1990 (Box 26, Folder 16)
    - Post-Warhol Hospital Controversy, 1985-1991 (Box 26, Folder 17)
    - Reviews and Comp Copies, 1987-1990 (Box 26, Folder 18)
    - Shooting, Solanas [Valerie] 1968, 1964-1969 (Box 26, Folder 19)
    - Oversize Andy Warhol Miscellaneous 3 of 6, 1968-1997 (Box 38, Folder 1)
    - Oversize Andy Warhol Miscellaneous 4 of 6, 1968-1997 (Box 38, Folder 2)
  - Designing the Earth: the Human Impulse to Shape Nature, 1955-1997; 3.9; 1.7 Linear feet Boxes 27-28
    Research subjects include earth art, Walter De Maria, Michael Heizer and Robert Smithson, moats, temples, and tombs.
    - Art, 1988-1995 (Box 27, Folder 1-2)
    - Commerce, 1987-1997 (Box 27, Folder 3)
    - De Maria, Walter, 1968-1993 (Box 27, Folder 4)
    - Dwellings, 1992-1996 (Box 27, Folder 5)
    - Earth Art - General, 1989-1997 (Box 27, Folder 6)
    - Earth Art General A (Bomarzo-Borglum), 1958-1990 (Box 27, Folder 7)
    - Earth Art General B (Noguchi-present), 1966-1995 (Box 27, Folder 8-10)
    - Earthworks Art, 1968-1991 (Box 27, Folder 11)
    - General, 1955-1996 (Box 27, Folder 12-13)
    - Heizer - Smithsonian, 1969-1990 (Box 27, Folder 14-16)
    - Moats (Motte & Mound Fr), 1971-1995 (Box 27, Folder 17)
    - Sacred Places, circa 1960-1995 (Box 28, Folder 1)
    - Shelter, Housing, 1963-1994 (Box 28, Folder 2-3)
    - Shelter, Housing - The Pueblo, the Hogan, 1969-1993 (Box 28, Folder 4)
    - Smithson, 1980-1994 (Box 28, Folder 5)
    - Temples, Cosmology, 1969-1995 (Box 28, Folder 6-7)
    - Temples - Rock Cut - India, circa 1991-1995 (Box 28, Folder 8)
    - Tombs, 1961-1994 (Box 28, Folder 9-10)
    - Warfare, circa 1971-1995 (Box 28, Folder 11)
- Printed Material, 1962-1997; 4; 9.4 Linear feet Boxes 28-39
  Arranged alphabetically by type of material, then chronologically where possible.
  Printed materials inlcude published books, clippings, gallery and museum literature, periodicals, three videos, and print versions of Bourdon’s writings. The most extensive coverage is of Bourdon’s published writings, and of Andy Warhol and his circle. Other subjects include animal welfare, dance, theatre, glass art (especially Dale Chihuly), modern art, and the art world. A number of materials are annotated by Bourdon, and there are also some autographs and dedications. Also included are some periodicals for which Bourdon served as an editor. Also found are scattered published books written by others about Andy Warhol, and other topics that interested Bourdon.
  - Books - by Andy Warhol, Annotated - Andy Warhol's Party Book by Andy Warhol and Pat Hackett, 1988 (Box 28, Folder 12)
  - Books - by Andy Warhol, Annotated - Blue Movie, 1970 (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - Books - by Andy Warhol, Annotated - The Philosophy of Andy Warhol (From A to B and Back Again), 1975 (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - Books - by Andy Warhol, Annotated - Popism: the Warhol 60s by Andy Warhol and Pat Hackett, 1980 (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - Books - by Andy Warhol, Annotated - Vanishing Animals by Andy Warhol and Kurt Benirschke, 1986 (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - Books - by Andy Warhol - Andy Warhol's Index (Book), 1967 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Andy Warhol Films and Paintings and untitled Institute of Contemporay Art U Penn, 1965, 1971 (Box 28, Folder 18)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Andy Warhol Death and Disasters and The Autobiography & Sex Life of Andy Warhol by John Wilcock et al, 1971, 1988 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Warhol by Victor Bockris, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Andy Warhol's Art and Films by Patrick S. Smith, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Loner at the Ball: The Life of Andy Warhol by Fred Lawrence Guiles, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Star Gazer by Stephen Koch, Andy Warhol: Portraits of the 70s by Robert Rosenblum, Andy Warhol, Transcript of David Bailey's ATV Documentary, 1974, 1979 (Box 29, Folder 5)
    Oversize material is housed in Box 39, Folder 5
  - Books - on Andy Warhol - Andy Warhol by Rainer Crone, 1970 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol - The Andy Warhol Museum, 1994 (Box 29, Folder 7)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol - The Life and Death of Andy Warhol by Victor Bockris, 1989 (Box 29, Folder 8)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Warhol by Christopher Makos and Out of the Shadow by Debra Miller, 1988, 1996 (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Andy Warhol Prints edited by Frayda Feldman and Jorg Schellmann and Andy Warhol Photographs by Stephen Koch, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol, Annotated - Warhol by Carter Ratcliff, 1983 (Box 30, Folder 3)
  - Books - on Andy Warhol - Warhol The Biography by Victor Bockris, 1989 (Box 30, Folder 4)
  - Books - Edie An American Biography by Jean Stein & George Plimpton (Bourdon Quoted), 1982 (Box 30, Folder 5)
  - Books - Gullibles Travels by Jill Johnston, 1974 (Box 30, Folder 6)
  - Books - S.C.U.M. Society for Cutting Up Men Manifesto by Valerie Solanas, 1968 (Box 30, Folder 7)
  - Books - Superstar by Viva, 1970 (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Books - to see the skies by Yoko Ono, 1990 (Box 30, Folder 9)
  - Clippings, 1966-1997 (Box 30, Folder 10-15)
  - Clippings, 1966-1997 (Box 31, Folder 1-16)
    Oversize material housed in Box 39, Folder 4
  - Clippings, 1966-1997 (Box 32, Folder 1-5)
  - Gallery & Museum Exhibitions - Andy Warhol, 1966, 1971 (Box 32, Folder 6)
  - Gallery & Museum Exhibitions - Andy Warhol, 1979, 1988-1989 (Box 32, Folder 7)
  - Gallery & Museum Exhibitions - Andy Warhol, 1992 (Box 32, Folder 8)
  - Gallery & Museum Exhibitions - Andy Warhol, 1994-1997 (Box 32, Folder 9)
    Oversize material is housed in Box 39, Folder 3
  - Gallery & Museum Announcements & Invitations, 1971, 1989-1997 (Box 32, Folder 10-11)
  - Gallery & Museum Booklets & Brochures, 1977, 1991-1997 (Box 32, Folder 11-17)
  - Gallery & Museum Booklets & Brochures, 1977, 1991-1992 (Box 33, Folder 1-2)
  - Gallery & Museum Press Releases, 1975-1997 (Box 33, Folder 3-10)
  - Periodicals, circa 1966-1976 (Box 33, Folder 11)
    Oversize Material is housed in Box 39, Folder 2
  - Periodicals by Andy Warhol - Parkett No. 12: Collaboration Andy Warhol, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 12)
  - Periodicals by Andy Warhol - Andy Warhol's Interview Vol IX No.1, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 13)
    Oversize material is housed in Box 39, Folder 1
  - Periodicals with material on Andy Warhol, 1967-1990 (Box 33, Folder 14-21)
  - Books - Andy Warhol, Contributor, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 22)
  - Books - Calder: Mobilist, Ringmaster, Innovator, 1980 (Box 33, Folder 23)
  - Books - Carl Andre, 1978 (Box 33, Folder 24)
  - Books - Jackie Ferrara Sculpture: A Retrospective, Contributor, 1992 (Box 33, Folder 25)
  - Books - Raid the Icebox 1 with Andy Warhol, Contributor, 1969 (Box 33, Folder 26)
  - Books - Warhol, 1989 (Box 34, Folder 1)
  - Published Writings, 1960-1965 (Box 34, Folder 2-7)
  - Published Writings, 1966-1973 (Box 34, Folder 8-12)
    Oversize material is housed in Box 39, Folder 6 and Box 38, Folder 3
  - Published Writings mostly Village Voice (173 shows), 1974-1977 (Box 34, Folder 13-15)
    Oversize materials housed in Box 38, Folder 3
  - Published Writings, 1978-1980 (Box 34, Folder 16-18)
  - Published Writings, 1981 (Box 34, Folder 19)
    Oversize material is housed in Box 38, Folder 3
  - Published Writings, 1982-1986 (Box 34, Folder 20-24)
  - Published Writings, 1987-1996 (Box 35, Folder 1-7)
  - Published Writings - du Magazine, New York Correspondent, 1976-1979 (Box 35, Folder 8-12)
  - Published Writings - Exhibitions, 1984, 1988 (Box 35, Folder 13)
  - Published Writings - Gallery & Exhibition Publications, 1975-1995 (Box 35, Folder 14)
  - GEO Magazine, 1982-1983 (Box 35, Folder 15-17)
  - Published Writings - Periodicals, 1962-1971 (Box 35, Folder 18-22)
  - Published Writings - Periodicals, 1972-1996 (Box 36, Folder 1-16)
  - Published Writings - Saturday Review of the Arts, 1972 (Box 36, Folder 17)
  - Video - Andy Warhol Presents Three Films by Paul Morrissey, Paramount Pictures, 1968, 1970, 1972 (Box 37, Folder 1)
  - Video - Warhol: Portrait of an Artist, London Weekend Television, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 2)
  - Oversize Published Writings 1970-1973 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Oversize Published Writings, 1977 (Box 38, Folder 3)
  - Oversize Published Writings, 1981 (Box 38, Folder 19)
  - Oversize Periodicals by Andy Warhol - Andy Warhol's Interview Vol IX, No. 1, 1978 (Box 39, Folder 1)
  - Oversize Periodicals, circa 1966-1996 (Box 39, Folder 2)
  - Oversize Gallery & Museum Exhibitions - Andy Warhol, 1994, 1997 (Box 39, Folder 9)
  - Oversize Clippings 15 of 27, 1966-1997 (Box 39, Folder 4)
  - Oversize Books - on Andy Warhol - Star Gazer, Andy Warhol: Portrait of the 70s, Andy Warhol Transcript of David Bailey's ATV Documentary, 1974, 1977 (Box 39, Folder 5)
  - Oversize Published Writings, 1966 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Oversize Published Writings, 1967 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Oversize Published Writings, 1968 (Box 39, Folder 6)
  - Oversize Published Writings, 1969 (Box 39, Folder 6)